Guide to the Office of the President Records, Sarah Gibson Blanding Files, 1911-1977 (bulk 1946-1964)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Office of the President Records, Sarah Gibson Blanding Files
1911-1977
1946-1964
Vassar College. Office of the President, Blanding, Sarah Gibson, 1898-1985
27.5 cubic feet (33 boxes); 1 oversize folder
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Records of the Vassar College Office of the President, correspondence, memoranda, clippings, articles, speeches, and press releases during her tenure at Vassar, 1946-1964, concerning women's education, academic freedom, 1950's politics, her stand against Congressional investigation of Communist influence in education, her introduction to Adlai Stevenson on a radio program, and her 1962 statement on pre-marital sex and Vassar students.
Biographical Note
Sarah Gibson Blanding, sixth president - and first woman president - of Vassar college, was born in Lexington, Kentucky in 1898. With her certificate from the New Haven Normal School of Gymnastics, she was offered two positions to teach physical education in high schools, but she took a similar position at the University of Kentucky for half the pay. Here she taught and studied, and received her B.A. in 1923. Her teaching and administrative abilities so impressed the university authorities that she was named acting dean at the age of twenty-four. After one year she left for Columbia University to earn an M.A. Two years later Miss Blanding studied at the London School of Economics with Harold Laski and then returned to the University of Kentucky as Dean of Women and teacher of political science until 1941. During these years, she lived on a 250-acre farm and raised tobacco of such high quality that it brought twice the going price.
Although a social scientist, not a home economist, in 1941 she became head of New York State College of Home Economics at Cornell, a position she held for five years. During World War II she served on the Joint Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation. She was also appointed to the War Department Civilian Advisory Council and to the Chief of Staff's National Civilian Advisory Committee for the Women's Army Corps.
When Miss Blanding was appointed president of Vassar in 1946, she not only took on the responsibilities of that office but also was called upon to serve on many public and private committees. She was successful in raising money for the college, hiring more male faculty members, increasing faculty salaries, introducing new curriculum, and bringing to Vassar the Mellon Fund grant for the study of personal growth and change during the college years. In 1964 she retired to her home in Lakeville, Connecticut, but continued to serve on the boards of numerous educational organizations. Blanding died in 1985 at the age of 86 at a retirement home in Newtown, Pennsylvania, where she had lived since 1980.
Scope and Content Note
The Vassar College Archives does not have a full set of official records for Miss Blanding's presidency. In 2002, 26 cartons of official material were removed from a collection previously associated with the presidency of her successor, Alan Simpson.
In addition to those boxes, there is a small collection of materials previously transferred to the archives, including: Correspondence, memoranda, clippings, articles, speeches, and press releases during her tenure at Vassar, 1946-1964. Subject matter includes women's education, academic freedom, 1950's politics, her stand against Congressional investigation of Communist influence in education, her introduction to Adlai Stevenson on a radio program, and her 14 April 1962 statement on pre-marital sex and Vassar students. Correspondence is largely letters received, including those from Marian Anderson, Elizabeth Bowen, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, Robert Oppenheimer, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Adlai Stevenson. Other items include scrapbooks, biographical articles, materials relating to her inauguration, diplomas, and citations, 1946-1985. There is also an undated travel diary of a trip to the British Isles (Gift of Barbara Austin Foote, VC 1940), and six letters to Jane Iglehart, VC 1943, purchased in 2006.
Access
Some files in this collection are restricted and labeled as such in the container list. The rest is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Additional material related to Sarah Gibson Blanding may be found in the Archives and Special Collections Library in:
Vassar College Biographical Files
Vassar College Photograph Files
See also, the Sarah Gibson Blanding Papers, Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study, Harvard University.
Subject Headings
Names:
Anderson, Marian, 1902-; Bowen, Elizabeth, 1899-1973; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965
Organizations:
Vassar College--Presidents; Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Public relations; Vassar College--Students
Subjects:
Communism in education; Communism--United States; Women--Social conditions; Women--Education; Women in politics; Premarital sex; Women--Diaries; Women college presidents; Women educators
Places:
United States--Social conditions; United States--Politics and government--20th century; British Isles--Description and travel
Document Types:
Correspondence; Diaries; Financial records; Reports; Scrapbooks
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Presidents
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, November 2006.
Updated by Zachary Bodnar and Laura Streett, December 2014.
Updated by Emma Gronbeck, December 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gifts of various donors; 2002 addition, transferred from the Vassar College Office of the President.
Arrangement
A small collection of Blanding material collected by the Vassar College Library is in the first 7 boxes. This smaller collection contains the 2006 addition of Iglehart letters. The larger part of the collection, the transfer of records from the Office of the President, is in another run of 26 boxes, which was described at the folder level in 2014.
Series List
- Original Library Collection, 1911-1964
- President's Office Transfer:
- Series I. Trustees and Administration, 1939-1964
- Series II. Buildings and Grounds, 1949-1968
- Series III. Faculty, 1933-1965
- Series IV. Gifts, 1926-1969
- Series V. Within the College, 1941-1969
- Series VI. Associations, 1932-1964
- Series VII. Centennial, 1956-1971
- Series VIII. Additions, 1943-1977
Container List
- Original Library Collection, 1911-1964
  - "Sex Statement" materials, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, the bulk of which relates to fund-raising, circa 1946-1962 (Box 1)
  - Letters to Jane Iglehart, 1946-1964 (Box 1)
  - Travel journal, British Isles, circa 1954 (Box 2)
  - Blanding chronology, circa 1964 (Box 2)
  - News clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, circa 1946-1964 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Inaugural material (Box 2)
  - Inaugural salutations (Boxes 3-4, 6)
  - Inauguration — Scrapbook, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Inaugural salutation - University of Kentucky, 1946 (Map Case — Drawer 29)
  - Miscellaneous certificates and honors, 1945-1946, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1940-1946 (Box 5)
  - Certificate of Appointment to the Public Advisory Board, 1949 Mar 2; (2 copies) (Map Case — Drawer 29)
  - Medallions and pins, circa 1946-1964 (Box 7)
  - Diary, 1911 (Box 7)
  - Honorary Degree and Letter from the University of Pennsylvania, undated (Map Case — Drawer 29)
  - Certificate of Appointment to the New York University Commission, 1946 Jul 13 (Map Case — Drawer 29)
- PRESIDENT'S OFFICE TRANSFER
- Series I. Trustees and Administration, 1939-1964
  - Agenda and Amendments, 1948-1956 (Folder 1.1)
  - Chairman Board of Trustees, 1945 Sep – 1948 Jul (Folder 1.2)
  - Chairman Board of Trustees, 1948 Jul – 1950 (Folder 1.3)
  - Chairman of the Board, 1950 Jul – 1953 (Folder 1.4)
  - Chairman of Board (Mrs. Mauck), 1953-1954 (Folder 1.5)
  - Trustees — A, 1953-1955 (Folder 1.6)
  - Trustees — B, 1956 Jul 1 – 1958 Jul 1 (Folder 1.8)
  - Trustees — B, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.8)
  - Trustees — C, 1951-1952 (Folder 1.9)
  - Trustees — G, 1953-1955 (Folder 1.10)
  - Trustees — H, 1954-1955 (Folder 1.11)
  - Trustees — L, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.12)
  - Trustees — L, 1951-1954 (Folder 1.13)
  - Trustees — M, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.14)
  - Trustees — M, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.15)
  - Trustees — N, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.16)
  - Trustees — P, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.17)
  - Trustees — R, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.18)
  - Trustees — R, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.19)
  - Trustees — S, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.20)
  - Trustees — T, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.21)
  - Trustees — V, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.22)
  - Trustees — W, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.23)
  - Trustees — W, 1956 Jul 1 – 1958 Jul 1 (Folder 1.24)
  - Trustees — W, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.25)
  - President’s Reports, 1940-1945 (Folder 1.26)
  - President’s Reports to Trustees, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.27)
  - President’s Reports to Trustees, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.28)
  - President’s Reports, 1956 Jul 1 – 1958 Jul 1 (Folder 1.29)
  - Former Trustees (Reunions), 1956 (Folder 1.30)
  - Secretary to the Board, 1946-1950 (Folder 1.31)
  - Budget Committee, 1949-1950 (Folder 1.32)
  - Budget Committee, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.33)
  - Budget Committee — Minutes, 1956 (Folder 1.34)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1945-1950 (Folder 1.35)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.36)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1939 Jul 1– 1958 Jul 1 (Folder 1.37)
  - Committee on Business Administration (Housing Reports), 1949-1950 (Folder 1.38)
  - Committee on Business Administration, 1949 (Folder 1.39)
  - Committee on Business Administration, 1949-1950 (Folder 1.40)
  - Business Administration Committee, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.41)
  - Endowment Committee, 1945-1950 (Folder 1.42)
  - Endowment, 1939-1944 (Folder 1.43)
  - Endowment Committee, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.44)
  - Endowment Committee, 1956 Jul 1 – 1958 Jul 1 (Folder 1.45)
  - Investments and Finance, 1939-1950 (Folder 1.46)
  - Committee on Investments and Finance, 1950 Jul – 1956 (Folder 1.47)
  - Nominations, 1940 Jun – 1948 Jun (Folder 1.48)
  - Committee on Nominations, 1952-1956 (Folder 1.49)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Life, 1946-1949 (Folder 1.50)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Life, 1950-1956 (Folder 1.51)
  - Special Committees, 1944-1946 (Folder 1.52)
  - Special Committee on College Health Services, 1946 (Folder 1.53)
  - Special Committee on Mellon Gift, 1949-1950 (Folder 1.54)
  - Trustee Faculty Committee to Nominate a President, 1945-1946 (Folder 1.55)
  - Committee on Size of College, 1946-1947 (Folder 1.56)
  - Committee on the Future of the College, 1951-1952 (Folder 1.57)
  - Committee on the Future of the College — Minutes of Meeting, 1951-1952 (Folder 1.58)
  - Joint Trustee-Faculty Committee on Expansion, 1955 (Folder 1.59)
  - Joint Committee of Alumnae-Trustees-Faculty, 1953 Jul – 1956 (Folder 1.60)
  - Trustee-Faculty Committee on Salary Scale, 1956 (Folder 1.61)
  - 100th Anniversary Committee, 1954-1956 (Folder 1.62)
  - Committee on Summer Institute, 1955-1956 (Folder 1.63)
  - Executive Committee, 1941 Dec – 1946 Apr (Folder 2.1)
  - Executive Committee — Minutes, 1946-1950 (Folder 2.2)
  - Executive Committee — Minutes, 1950-1956 (Folder 2.3)
  - Executive Committee — Minutes, 1956 Jul – 1958 Jul (Folder 2.4)
  - Executive Committee — Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Folder 2.5)
  - Executive Committee — Correspondence, 1952 (Folder 2.6)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee — Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Folder 2.7)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1939-1950 (Folder 2.8)
  - Faculty and Studies — Minutes, 1950-1956 (Folder 2.9)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1956 Jul – 1958 Jul (Folder 2.10)
  - Comptroller — General, 1946-1949 (Folder 2.11)
  - Comptroller — General, 1950-1956 (Folder 2.12)
  - Comptroller re Salaries, 1952-1956 (Folder 2.13)
  - Treasurer, 1945-1950 (Folder 2.14)
  - Treasurer, 1950 Sep – 1953 Jan (Folder 2.15)
  - Treasurer, 1953–1956 (Folder 2.16)
  - Mr. Richards, 1945 Aug – 1948 Jul (Folder 2.17)
  - Mr. Richards, 1948–1950 (Folder 2.18)
  - General Manager, 1950–1953 (Folder 2.19)
  - General Manager, 1954–1956 (Folder 2.20)
  - General Manager’s Reports, 1941 Oct – 1950 May (Folder 2.21)
  - Reports of General Manager, 1950-1956 (Folder 2.22)
  - General Manager, 1956 Jul – 1958 Jul (Folder 2.23)
  - Director of Halls, 1954 (Folder 2.24)
  - Personnel Office, 1955 (Folder 2.25)
  - Chairman of the Board, 1958–1960 (Folder 2.26)
  - Chairman of the Board — Mrs. Barach, 1960 Jul – 1961 Jul (Folder 2.27)
  - Chairman of the Board — Mrs. Wilkie, 1961 May 15 – 1962 (Folder 2.28)
  - Trustees —B, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.29)
  - Trustees — D, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.30)
  - Trustees — D, 1958 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.31)
  - Trustees — G, 1958 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.32)
  - Trustees — G, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.33)
  - Trustees — H, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.34)
  - Trustees — L, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.35)
  - Trustees — M, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.36)
  - Trustees — N, 1958 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.37)
  - Trustees — N, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.38)
  - Trustees — P, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.39)
  - Trustees — R, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.40)
  - Trustees — S, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.41)
  - Board of Trustees — General, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.42)
  - President’s Report to Trustees, 1958 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.43)
  - Revision of the Governance, 1962 (Folder 2.44)
  - Trustee Committee on Admission, 1959-1960 (Folder 2.45)
  - Budget Committee, 1957-1958 (Folder 2.46)
  - Budget Committee, 1960 (Folder 2.47)
  - Budget Committee — Minutes, 1960 Jul (Folder 2.48)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1960 Jul (Folder 2.49)
  - Committee on Business Administration, 1960 Jul (Folder 2.50)
  - Committee on Campus Development (Mrs. Hadley’s File), 1960-1962 (Folder 2.51)
  - Committee on Campus Development, 1961-1962 (Folder 2.52)
  - Development Committee, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 2.53)
  - Investments and Finance Committee — Minutes, 1961 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.1)
  - Investments and Finance Committee — Minutes, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.2)
  - Report to Joint Trustee-Faculty Committee (Mabel Newcomer), 1960 Apr (Folder 3.3)
  - Joint Trustee-Faculty Committee Supplementary Material, 1959 Summer (Folder 3.4)
  - Joint Trustee-Faculty-Administration Committee on the Ruml-Morrison Report, 1960 (Folder 3.5)
  - Joint Trustee-Faculty-Administration Committee on the Ruml-Morrison Report, 1959-1960 (Folder 3.6)
  - Sub-Committee on the Ruml Report, 1959 (Folder 3.7)
  - Trustee Sub-Committee on Mellon Fund, 1961-1962 (Folder 3.8)
  - Committee on Nominations, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.9)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Life, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.10)
  - Executive Committee — Correspondence, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.11)
  - Executive Committee — Minutes, 1958 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.12)
  - Executive Committee — Minutes, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.13)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1958 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.14)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.15)
  - Comptroller — General, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.16)
  - Comptroller — National Defense Student Loan Program, 1959-1961 (Folder 3.17)
  - Treasurer, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.18)
  - Treasurer — Mr. Welch, 1961 May 15 (Folder 3.19)
  - General Manager, 1958 Jul 1 – 1959 Jul 1 (Folder 3.20)
  - General Manager, 1959 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.21)
  - General Manager, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.22)
  - General Manager, 1961 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.23)
  - General Manager — Reports, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.24)
  - General Manager — Food Survey, 1961-1963 (Folder 3.25)
  - Union Negotiations, 1962 (Folder 3.26)
  - Personnel Office, 1960 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.27)
  - Department of Halls, 1958 Jul 1 - (Folder 3.28)
  - Mr. Harold Howe’s Committee — Mr. John Wilkie, 1963 (Folder 4.1)
  - Trustees — B, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.2)
  - Trustees — C, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.3)
  - Trustees — D, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.4)
  - Trustees — E, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.5)
  - Trustees — F, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.6)
  - Trustees — H, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.7)
  - Trustees — L, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.8)
  - Trustees — M, 1962 Jul (Folder 4.9)
  - Trustees — N, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.10)
  - Trustees — P, 1964-1965 (Folder 4.11)
  - Trustees — R, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.12)
  - Trustees — S, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.13)
  - Trustees — V, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.14)
  - Trustees — W, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.15)
  - Trustees — General, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.16)
  - President Elect, 1962-1965 (Folder 4.17)
  - Redecoration of President’s House for President-Elect, 1963-1964 (Folder 4.18)
  - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.19)
  - Budget Committee Minutes, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.20)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.21)
  - Development Committee, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.22)
  - President’s Report to Trustees, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.23)
  - Chairman of the Board — Mr. Wilkie, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.24)
  - Vassar — John Wilkie, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.25)
  - Comptroller — General, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.26)
  - Comptroller re Salaries, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.27)
  - Comptroller — Major Medical, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.28)
  - Comptroller — National Defense Student Loan Program, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.29)
  - Investments and Finance Committee, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.30)
  - Committee on Nominations, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.31)
  - Committee on undergraduate Life, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.32)
  - Executive Committee — Minutes, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.33)
  - Executive Committee — Correspondence, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.34)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.35)
  - Treasurer — Mr. Welch, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.36)
  - Treasurer — Norman Smith, 1963-1964 (Folder 4.37)
  - Prospective Treasurer, 1962-1963 (Folder 4.38)
  - General Manager, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.39)
  - General Manager Reports, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.40)
  - Union Negotiations and Contracts, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.41)
  - Department of Halls, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.42)
  - Personnel Office, 1962 Jul 1 - (Folder 4.43)
  - Mr. Howe’s Committee — Sarah Gibson Blanding, 1963 Oct 19 (Folder 4.44)
- Series II. Buildings and Grounds, 1949-1968
  - Chapel, 1952-1954 (Folder 5.1)
  - Chicago Hall Dedication, 1959 (Folder 5.2)
  - Chicago Hall Furnishings, 1958 (Folder 5.3)
  - Chicago Hall, 1957-1961 (Folder 5.4)
  - Language House, 1953-1957 (Folder 5.5)
  - Chapel Organ and Acoustics and Alterations, 1965-1966 (Folder 5.6)
  - Church House, 1965 (Folder 5.7)
  - Consulting Architect, 1950-1961 (Folder 5.8)
  - Consulting Decorator, 1951 (Folder 5.9)
  - Consulting Landscape Architect, 1959 (Folder 5.10)
  - Cooperative House Furnishings (Mr. Breuer’s Plans and final set up), 1950-1951 (Folder 5.11)
  - Cooperative House, 1949-1953 (Folder 5.12)
  - Ellis House, 1963-1964 (Folder 5.13)
  - Faculty Housing — Hooker-Raymond Avenue Triangle, 1960-1966 (Folder 5.14)
  - Faculty Housing, 1960-1966 (Folder 5.15)
  - Jeannette K. Watson Faculty Apartments, 1966-1967 (Folder 5.16)
  - Faculty Housing — Watson Project, 1965-1966 (Folder 5.17)
  - Faculty Housing Project Committee on Landscaping and Sculpture, 1965 (Folder 5.18)
  - Faculty Housing — Requests for Purchase of Single Houses, 1960 (Folder 5.19)
  - Cooperative House Furnishings (Mrs. Draper’s suggestions), 1950 (Folder 5.20)
  - Ferrell House, 1957 (Folder 5.21)
  - Main Building Alterations, 1960 (Folder 5.22)
  - Mr. Saarinen’s Plans for Main Obsolete, 1954-1955 (Folder 5.23)
  - Renovation of Main Building, 1955-1962 (Folder 5.24)
  - Main Building — Proposed Student Room Alterations, 1962-1963 (Folder 5.25)
  - Main building Cupola, 1962 (Folder 5.26)
  - Taylor Hall Alterations, 1959-1965 (Folder 5.27)
  - Taylor Hall — Sculpture Court, 1963 (Folder 5.28)
  - Williams House, 1950 (Folder 5.29)
  - Financing Construction for Entire College, 1964 (Folder 5.30)
  - Central Dining Room, 1962-1965 (Folder 5.31)
  - Economic Feasibility of Consolidation of Food Service Facilities, 1962 Apr 23 (Folder 5.32)
  - Consulting Decorator (Mrs. Pemberton), 1953-1968 (Folder 5.33)
  - Noyes House, 1955-1959 (Folder 6.1)
  - Noyes House Furnishings, 1958-1959 (Folder 6.2)
  - Eero Saarinen Associates, 1954-1957 (Folder 6.3)
  - Emma Hartman Noyes House (Dedication), 1958 (Folder 6.4)
  - Kendrick, 1953-1961 (Folder 6.5)
  - Library Addition (B) — Elizabeth Stillman Williams Wing, 1959-1962 (Folder 6.6)
  - Library Addition (A), 1961-1963 (Folder 6.7)
  - Library Ceremony, 1963 Oct 19 (Folder 6.8)
- Series III. Faculty, 1933-1965
  - Current Faculty, 1957-1958 (Folder 6.9)
  - Current Faculty, 1956-1957 (Folder 6.10)
  - Current Faculty, 1955-1956 (Folder 6.11)
  - Current Faculty, 1954-1955 (Folder 6.12)
  - Current Faculty, 1953-1954 (Folder 6.13)
  - Current Faculty, 1952-1953 (Folder 6.14)
  - Faculty, 1951-1952 (Folder 6.15)
  - Faculty, 1950-1951 (Folder 6.16)
  - Faculty, 1949-1950 (Folder 6.17)
  - Faculty, 1948-1949 (Folder 6.18)
  - Faculty, 1947-1948 (Folder 6.19)
  - Faculty, 1946-1947 (Folder 6.20)
  - Contracts, 1948-1949 (Folder 6.21)
  - Contracts, 1949-1950 (Folder 6.22)
  - Contracts, 1950-1951 (Folder 6.23)
  - Notices Sent to Present Faculty — Recommendations, 1952-1953 (Folder 6.24)
  - Contracts, 1951-1952 (Folder 6.25)
  - Contracts, 1952-1953 (Folder 6.26)
  - Notices Sent to Faculty — Contracts, 1953-1954 (Folder 6.27)
  - Contracts, 1953-1954 (Folder 7.1)
  - Contracts, 1954-1955 (Folder 7.2)
  - Contracts, 1955-1956 (Folder 7.3)
  - Contracts, 1956-1957 (Folder 7.4)
  - Contracts, 1957-1958 (Folder 7.5)
  - Current Faculty, 1958-1959 (Folder 7.6)
  - Contracts — A-L, 1958-1959 (Folder 7.7)
  - Contracts — M-Z, 1958-1959 (Folder 7.8)
  - Current Faculty, 1959-1960 (Folder 7.9)
  - Contracts, 1959-1960 (Folder 7.10)
  - Current Faculty, 1960-1961 (Folder 7.11)
  - Contracts — A-L, 1960-1961 (Folder 7.12)
  - Contracts — M-Z, 1960-1961 (Folder 7.13)
  - Current Faculty, 1961-1962 (Folder 7.14)
  - Contracts — A-L, 1961-1962 (Folder 7.15)
  - Contracts — M-Z, 1961-1962 (Folder 7.16)
  - Current Faculty, 1962-1963 (Folder 8.1)
  - Contracts — A-M, 1962-1963 (Folder 8.2)
  - Contracts — M-Z, 1962-1963 (Folder 8.3)
  - Current Faculty, 1963-1964 (Folder 8.4)
  - Contracts, 1963-1964 (Folder 8.5)
  - Officers — Dean, 1946-1949 (Folder 8.6)
  - Officers — Committee on Admission, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.7)
  - Assistant Dean, 1944-1947 (Folder 8.8)
  - Vocational Bureau, 1946-1948 (Folder 8.9)
  - Appointments — Dean, 1948 (Folder 8.10)
  - Fait, Marion (Folder 8.11)
  - Board of Residents — Warden, 1948 (Folder 8.12)
  - Officers — Warden, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.13)
  - Miss Pillsbury and Miss McCaleb, 1947 (Folder 8.14)
  - Appointments — Library, 1946-1947 (Folder 8.15)
  - Officers — Library, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.16)
  - Board of Residents — Warden, 1946-1947 (Folder 8.17)
  - Appointments — Warden, 1946 (Folder 8.18)
  - Appointments — Art, 1946-1949 (Folder 8.19)
  - Officers — Art, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.20)
  - Appointments — Astronomy, 1946-1948 (Folder 8.21)
  - Officers — Astronomy, 1946-1949 (Folder 8.22)
  - Appointments — Chemistry, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.23)
  - Officers — Chemistry, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.24)
  - Child Study — Appointments, 1946-1948 (Folder 8.25)
  - Officers — Child Study, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.26)
  - Appointments — Classical Languages and Literature, 1948 (Folder 8.27)
  - Officers — Classical Languages and Literature, 1948-1949 (Folder 8.28)
  - Appointments — Drama, 1946-1948 (Folder 8.29)
  - Officers — Drama, 1945-1949 (Folder 8.30)
  - Appointments — Economics, 1946 (Folder 8.31)
  - Officers — Economics, 1945-1948 (Folder 8.32)
  - Appointments — English, 1945-1948 (Folder 8.33)